Kraushaar Galleries
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Outgoing Letters, 1920-1945, Series 1:; (boxes 1-9; 9 linear ft.)
  - P, General, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    (Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts; Pennsylvania Museum of Art; Charles Prendergast)
  - R, General, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - S, General, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    (San Francisco Art Association; Henry E. Schnakenberg; John Sloan)
  - Charles Sessler, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - T, General, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Tovell, Harold M., 1934 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - V, General, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - W, General, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - X-Y-Z, General, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - A, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - B, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - C, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    (Courvoisier Galleries)
  - D, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    (Charles Demuth before his death; Denver Art Museum; Guy Pène Du Bois)
  - E, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - F, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - G, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    (Edith Glackens; William J. Glackens)
  - Wm. E. Goodridge & Son, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - H, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    (Harriet C. Hanley; Dalzell Hatfield)
  - Harrison, Preston, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - I, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - J, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - K, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - L, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - M, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Miller, Harriette, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - N, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - O, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - P, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Q, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - R, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - S, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    (John Sloan)
  - Seachrest, Effie, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - T, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - U, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - V, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - W, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - X-Y-Z, General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - A, General, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    (Addison Gallery of American Art; Art Institute of Chicago)
  - B, General, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - C, General, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Cleveland Museum of Art, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - D, General, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    (Guy Pène Du Bois)
  - E, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - F, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - G, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    (George A. Gay describing new galleries at 730 Fifth Avenue)
  - Goodman-Walker, Inc., 1936 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Wm. E. Goodridge & Son, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - H, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    (Preston Harrison; Helen Hayes; High Museum of Art)
  - I, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - J, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - K, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - L, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Lyman Allyn Museum, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - M, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    (Harriette Miller discussing Henry E. Schnakenberg)
  - N, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    (Thomas W. Nason concerning consignment of his prints)
  - O, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - P, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    (Duncan Phillips; Marjorie Phillips; Charles Prendergast)
  - Q, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - R, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - S, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    (Dolly Sloan; John Sloan; Mr. and Mrs. H. S. Southam)
  - Charles Sessler, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - T, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    (Toledo Museum of Art)
  - U, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - V, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - W, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    (Charles A. Whelan)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - X-Y-Z, General, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - A, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - B, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - C, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Cleveland Museum of Art, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Courvoisier Galleries, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - D, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - E, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - F, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - G, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    (Edith Glackens; William J. Glackens; Goodman-Walker, Inc.)
  - Wm. E. Goodridge & Son, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - H, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    (T. E. Hanley; Preston Harrison)
  - I, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - J, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - K, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    (Charles Kaeselau concerning selection of watercolors for consignment)
  - L, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - M, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - N, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - O, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - P, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    (Duncan Phillips; Marjorie Phillips, Charles Prendergast; Vincent Price)
  - Q, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - R, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - S, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    (Dolly Sloan; John Sloan)
  - Sweet Briar College, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - T, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - U, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - V, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - W, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    (Forbes Watson; Nan Watson)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - X-Y-Z, General, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - A, General, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    (Arts Club of Washington)
  - Addison Gallery of American Art, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - B, General, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    (Gifford Beal concerning his decision to break off relations with Kraushaar Galleries; Reynolds Beal)
  - C, General, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    (Carnegie Institute; Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center)
  - D, General, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    (Randall Davey; Guy Pène Du Bois; Jacques Dubourg)
  - E, General, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Edminston, Rodman W., 1938 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - F, General, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - G, General, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    (Edith Glackens following the death of William J. Glackens)
  - Goodman-Walker, Inc., 1938 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    (Nelson Goodman)
  - Wm. E. Goodridge & Son, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - H, General, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    (Hackley Art Gallery; Preston Harrison)
  - I, General, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - J, General, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - K, General, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    (Charles Kaeselau; Henry G. Keller; Berthe C. Koch concerning a Du Bois exhibition and referring to him as an outstanding painter)
  - L, General, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    (Richard Lahey; Charles Locke)
  - Laporte, William F., 1938 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - M, General, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    (Harriette Miller; Minneapolis Institute of Arts)
  - Museum of Modern Art and Museum of Modern Art Gallery of Washington, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - N, General, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - O, General, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - P, General, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Q, General, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - R, General, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    (Edward G. Robinson regarding purchase of a Maurice Prendergast painting)
  - S, General, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    (Charles Sessler; Dolly Sloan; John Sloan)
  - T, General, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    (Augustus Vincent Tack concerning financial account; Harold M. Tovell)
  - Toledo Museum of Art, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - U, General, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - V, General, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - W, General, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - X-Y-Z, General, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - A, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    (Addison Gallery of American Art regarding Elizabeth S. Navas's development of the Roland P. Murdock Collection; Art Center School in Los Angeles)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - B, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    (Jozef Bakos concerning consignment of his watercolors; Gifford Beal)
  - C, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    (Corcoran Gallery of Art)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - D, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    (Randall Davey; Walt Dehner regarding consignment of his watercolors; Jacques Dubourg)
  - E, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    (Arthur F. Egner concerning disagreements with Isabel Nagle Lachaise over casting of sculpture by her late husband, Gaston Lachaise)
  - F, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - G, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    (Mrs. William Steele Gray)
  - Wm. E. Goodridge & Son, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - H, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    (T. E. Hanley; Parker Morse Hooper)
  - Hatfield, Dalzell, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - I, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - J, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - K, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    (Charles Kaeselau; John Koch)
  - L, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    (Richard Lahey; Los Angeles Museum of History, Science and Art)
  - M, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    (Harriette Miller; Museum of Fine Arts, Boston)
  - N, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - O, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - P, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    (Duncan Phillips; Charles Prendergast; Eugenie Prendergast)
  - Q, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - R, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - S, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    (Dolly Sloan; John Sloan; Sweet Briar College)
  - Charles Sessler, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Southam, H. S., 1939 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - T, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Toledo Museum of Art, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - U, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - V, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - W, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    (Washington County Museum of Fine Arts; Lewis B. Williams)
  - Warner, Ruth, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - X-Y-Z, General, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - A, General, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Addison Gallery of American Art, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - B, General, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    (Gifford Beal)
  - C, General, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    (Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center; Evangeline Cozzens)
  - D, General, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    (Randall Davey; Walt Dehner; Guy Pène Du Bois)
  - E, General, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - F, General, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - G, General, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    (Edith Glackens)
  - Goodman-Walker, Inc., 1940 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Wm. E. Goodridge & Son, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - H, General, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Hatfield, Dalzell, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - I, General, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - J, General, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    (Marion Junkin)
  - K, General, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    (Charles Kaeselau; Henry G. Keller)
  - L, General, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    (Isabel Nagle Lachaise; Richard Lahey; Charles Locke)
  - M, General, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - N, General, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    (National Gallery of Canada regarding sale of Maurice Prendergast's Picnic; establishing a business relationship with Woldemar Neufeld)
  - William Rockhill Nelson Gallery of Art, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    (John Koch exhibition)
  - O, General, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - P, General, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Phillips, Duncan, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Q, General, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - R, General, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - S, General, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    (John Sloan regarding financial arrangements)
  - T, General, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - U, General, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - V, General, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - W, General, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    (Washington County Museum of Fine Arts; Esther Williams)
  - Warner, Ruth, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - X-Y-Z, General, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - A, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    (Albany Institute of History and Art documenting Antoinette Kraushaar's interest in drawings)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - B, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    (Gifford Beal regarding payment on his account; Reynolds Beal; Louis Bouché; establishing a business relationship with Samuel Brecher; Brooklyn Museum of Art)
  - C, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    (Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center)
  - D, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - E, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - F, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    (William Dean Fausett; Vaughn Flannery concerning becoming his dealer)
  - G, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Goodman-Walker, Inc., 1941 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Wm. E. Goodridge & Son, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - H, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - I, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - J, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - K, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    (Charles Kaeselau; Henry G. Keller; John Koch regarding his account)
  - L, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    (Isabel Nagle Lachaise; Richard Lahey)
  - M, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    (Minneapolis Institute of Arts)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - N, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    (Woldemar Neufeld)
  - O, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - P, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Q, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - R, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    (establishing a business relationship with Boardman Robinson; Rockford Art Association; Andrée Ruellan)
  - S, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    (apologizing to John Sloan for events that have led to his dissatisfaction with the handling of his work)
  - T, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - U, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    (University of Missouri concerning defacing of a John Sloan drawing)
  - V, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - W, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    (Worcester Art Museum expressing an opinion on which painters have had a reputation or an influence that has been "undeniable")
  - X-Y-Z, General, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - A, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    (Artists for Victory)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - B, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - C, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - D, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    (Walt Dehner; attorney Nicholas Donnelly concerning family finances)
  - E, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - F, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    (William Dean Fausett expressing opinions of his work; Vaughn Flannery; Julianna Force)
  - G, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Wm. E. Goodridge & Son, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - H, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 58)
    (John Hartell; John Heliker)
  - I, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - J, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - K, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    (John Koch expressing opinions on his work)
  - L, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - M, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - N, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - O, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - P, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - R, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    (Boardman Robinson regarding his illustrations for Moby Dick and Spoon River Anthology; Andrée Ruellan)
  - S, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - T, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - U, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - V, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - W, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 72)
    (Esther Williams)
  - X-Y-Z, General, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - A, General, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 74)
    (Addison Gallery of American Art; American Federation of Arts)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - B, General, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 76)
    (Baltimore Museum of Art; Louis Bouché)
  - C, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    (Corcoran Gallery of Art regarding a gift of 3 drawings by William J. Glackens; Russell Cowles; Evangeline Cozzens)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - D, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    (Walt Dehner; Detroit Institute of Arts; Guy Pène Du Bois)
  - E, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    (Fritz Ehrenfest; Paul Ehrenfest)
  - F, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    (William Dean Fausett; Gershon Fenster; Vaughn Flannery)
  - G, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    (Nelson Goodman; homorous letter to Earle Grant describing the gallery scene in New York)
  - Wm. E. Goodridge & Son, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - H, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Hartell, John, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    (exhibition of his work that was critically acclaimed)
  - I, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - J, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - K, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - L, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - M, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - N, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    (New Britain Institute)
  - O, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    (Oberlin College Allen Memorial Art Museum)
  - P, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Phillips, Duncan, and Marjorie Phillips, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Q, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - R, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    (Boardman Robinson)
  - S, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    (John Sloan; Katharine Sturgis)
  - T, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - U, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - V, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - W, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Willson, Caroline, and Donald B. Willson, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - X-Y-Z, General, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - A, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    (Artists for Victory expressing concern over a London exhibition)
  - B, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    (Gifford Beal; Reynolds Beal; Louis Bouché)
  - C, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    (Cleveland Museum of Art; Russell Cowles; Evangeline Cozzens; Cranbrook Academy of Art)
  - D, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    (Walt Dehner; Guy Pène Du Bois)
  - E, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - F, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    (William Dean Fausett; Gerson Fenster; Vaughn Flannery)
  - G, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Wm. E. Goodridge & Son, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - H, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    (John Hartell; Dalzell Hatfield)
  - I, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - J, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    (Marion Junkin concerning poor sales of her work)
  - K, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    (Henry G. Keller; John Koch)
  - L, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    (Richard Lahey; Little Gallery)
  - M, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    (Lucia McBride; Museum of Modern Art regarding exhibition of The Eight)
  - N, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    (Elizabeth S. Navas)
  - O, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    (Georgia O'Keeffe)
  - P, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 44)
    (Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts regarding purchase of John Sloan's Jefferson Market; Charles Prendergast; Eugenie Prendergast)
  - Q, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - R, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 46)
    (Boardman Robinson; Alice Roullier; Andrée Ruellan)
  - S, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    (Helen Farr Sloan; John Sloan; Alix W. Stanley)
  - T, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 48)
    (Toledo Museum of Art; Helen Train)
  - U, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 49)
    (University of Nebraska)
  - V, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - W, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 51)
    (Witte Memorial Museum)
  - X-Y-Z, General, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 52)
    (Edmund Yaghjian; Mahonri Mackintosh Young)
  - A, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - B, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    (Jozef Bakos; Louis Bouché; Samuel Brecher)
  - C, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - D, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 56)
    (Walt Dehner)
  - E, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - F, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 58)
    (William Dean Fausett; Vaughn Flannery)
  - G, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - H, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 60)
    (John Hartell)
  - I, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - J, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - K, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - L, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - M, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - N, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - O, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - P, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - R, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 69)
    (Boardman Robinson; Andrée Ruellan)
  - S, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - T, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - U, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - V, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - W, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - X-Y-Z, General, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 75)
- Incoming Letters, circa 1901-1944, Series 2:; (boxes 10-26; 16.25 ft.)
  This series contains letters written in response, or relation to, those in Series 1, and many of the significant correspondents in that series are also represented in Series 2. Of additional interest is the substantial correspondence from other artists including Joseph Barber, Gifford Beal, Reynolds Beal, Randall Davey, Walt Dehner, Charles Demuth, William Dean Fausett, Vaughn Flannery, Henry Keller, Richard Lahey, Charles Prendergast, Boardman Robinson, Iver Rose, Andrée Ruellan, Henry Schnakenberg, John Sloan, Katharine Sturgis, Esther Williams, and Mahonri Young. The series also contains regular letters from Guy Pène Du Bois, in Europe, that express personal feelings about his work and recurrent financial problems. Gaston Lachaise was also a regular correspondent who submitted frequent requests for financial assistance. After his death his work was handled by his wife, Isabel Nagle Lachaise, and the series documents the often difficult relations between Isabel Lachaise and Kraushaar Galleries. Letters from Edith and Ira Glackens demonstrate the mutual affection and respect between the Glackens family and the Kraushaars. The series contains only three short letters from Maurice Prendergast, with one describing his eagerness to exhibit at Kraushaar Galleries in December 1921, and three short letters from George Luks, which unfortunately supply little information about his work.
  Correspondence with Gifford Beal, Reynolds Beal, Harriette Miller, Henry Schnakenberg, and Esther Williams illustrate the depth of the Kraushaar family's relationship with the Rockport art community, which extended beyond business to close personal friendships. Throughout the collection there is evidence that Antoinette Kraushaar continued a tradition of regular vacations to the area also enjoyed by her father.
  The series contains substantial correspondence from Duncan Phillips. The descriptions of his enthusiasm for individual artists and specific pieces provide valuable documentation of his developing tastes. Regular and lengthy letters from Preston Harrison are full of lively information about the California art scene. Substantive correspondence with Elizabeth S. Navas begins in this series and documents the role that Kraushaar Galleries played in her goal to assemble the Roland P. Murdock Collection of the Wichita Art Museum under the terms of the will of Navas's friend, Louise Caldwell Murdock.
  Additional incoming correspondence dating from 1901-1944 is found in Series 6.1.
  Records are arranged chronologically and alphabetically by correspondent within each year. Nine folders of undated letters can be found at the beginning of the series. Letters from correspondents whose names are illegible or not recorded are also placed at the beginning of the appropriate year. Folders for "Miscellaneous Notes," "Bills," and "Receipts" are filed at the end of the year to which they relate.
  - Bonheur, Rosa, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Du Bois, Guy Pène, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Geissbuhler, Arnold, and Elisabeth Geissbuhler, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - H, General, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    (Ernst Halberstadt)